NYSUT Mid-Hudson Regional Office Files. 6174/011
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- GCDA-Bus Driver Grievance, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  Transportation memo from transportation supervisor to bus driver, re grievance, February 7, 1991; grievance by LaPlante, February 1; memo re bidding procedure, February 22; grievance by bus driver, March 12; grievance by bus driver, March 12; memos requesting second and third stage grievance proceedings, February 11 and 25; letter from clerk of Board of Education, indicating that board found grievance had merit, noting remuneration would be forthcoming, April 9
- GCDC-Grievance, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  First and second stage grievances re failure to offer bid on extra run
- GCDC-Transportation Memo, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  Memo to all drivers re new bid board for field trips, noting basketball trips would be treated the same as any other extra trip, March 26, 1991; memo to drivers re basketball schedule, December 10, 1990
- GCDC-Grievance, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 31)
- GCDC-Grievance, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  First and second stage grievances; related correspondence
- GCDA-Sick Pool Establishment, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  Authorization form for contribution to sick leave pool; memo to bargaining unit members re sick leave pool; related correspondence
- Greenville-Cust. Driv., 1988 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  Grievance form on behalf of mechanic-bus driver; job application; related correspondence
- GCDA-Driver General Info., 1988 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  Grievances; job descriptions for head driver and head custodian
- HTA Grievance, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  Agreement between Hudson City School District and Hudson Teachers' Association, July 1, 1988, through June 30, 1991; formal grievance, HTA vs Hudson City School District, re workload and professional disadvantage in assignment of low-achieving students, 3/16/90; handwritten notes re Boffa; handwritten notes re low-achieving student
- Psychiatric Examination, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  Letter from schools superintendent, ordering psychiatric examination; handwritten confidential psychiatric report, recommending physical evaluation; letter from district, ordering physical examination
- Hudson TA Resignation, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  Correspondence, Hudson Teachers' Association president and NYSUT Mid-Hudson field representative re failure to represent; handwritten notes
- Worker's Compensation Issue, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  NYS Workers' Compensation Board Notice of Decision, 7/28/89; related correspondence from NYSUT field representative Linda Stanczik re whether employee owed district remainder of compensation award or whether district owed employee restoration of sick time
- Hudson Coaching Grievance, 1985-1991 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  Grievance form re failure to appoint as head coach; correspondence from attorneys; newspaper clipping; agreement between Hudson City School District and Hudson Teachers' Association, 1985-88; teachers' salary schedule; handwritten notes
- WCT-Health Concern, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  Letter to schools superintendent expressing health concern re installation of new carpeting, noting poor ventilation, absence of windows, and complaints from faculty and students after earlier installation
- Hudson-McLoughlin, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  Memo from art teacher to principal of J. L. Edwards School, requesting relief from non-instructional duties, November 1, 1993; handwritten notes re art teacher, 10/27/93; grievance; opinion and award in the matter of arbitration between Hudson Teachers Association and Hudson City School District, re work load, August 22, 1983; opinion in arbitration re work load, 1978
- Hudson School District, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  Notice of Petition and Petition before the Commissioner of Education in the matter of the appeal of teacher from the actions taken by the Board of Education of the Hudson City School District; Stipulation of Settlement, 1991; grievance on behalf of teacher re emergency personal leave; correspondence re dismissal of teacher by Germantown Central School; teacher evaluation forms; typed notes of meeting with school officials re dismissal
- Hudson-TA, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  Notes re Hudson settlement; teacher salary schedule; teachers association Board of Education election plan
- Hudson-Legal, 1978-1987 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  Letter from NYSUT filed representative to schools superintendent re takeover by BOCES of district's alternate education program, January 23, 1987; letter from district advising teacher that he would be reassigned to teach at Alternate Learning Center, June 23, 1978; list of questions re reassignment; case law
- Hudson-Improper Practice Charge, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  Letter from president of Hudson Teachers Association to NYSUT Mid-Hudson field representative, demanding that NYSUT take the lead in filing an improper practice charge against the Hudson City School District, also questioning why HTA was not consulted in planning a regional conference with BOCES; improper practice charge by Hudson Teachers Association re BOCES conference
- Hudson-Contract and Constitution, 1980-1985 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  Agreement 1982-85 between the Hudson City School District and the Hudson Teachers Association; 1980-82 agreement; HTA constitution
- Hudson Middle School-End of Year Problem, 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  Memo to middle school principal from Professional Standards Committee advising that HTA considered various requirements for end of school year violations of contract, July 1, 1983; Demand for Arbitration by HTA, November 11, 1983; letter from HTA to president of Hudson Board of Education re whether matter was a grievance, November 15, 1983; letter from American Arbitration Association tribunal administrator, advising that the matter had been settled, February 28, 1984
- Hudson-Misc., 1978-1980 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  Agreement 1978-1980 between the Hudson City School District and the Hudson Teachers' Association; request for NYSUT legal opinion re pending layoffs, May 9, 1979
- Hudson-TA P.R. Project, 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  Materials re "Inside Your Schools" video tapes and program script; memos and mock-up of "good news" cards to be sent home to parents re student progress, October 18, 1985; memo re staff directory
- Hudson-TA E.I.T. Negotiations, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 51)
  6/9. Letter from NYSUT president Tom Hobart to local presidents, announcing the availability of Excellence in Teaching funds to improve salaries, attributing the lobbying efforts of VOTE/COPE for the funding, May 23, 1986, with attached question and answer sheet re program; Regulations of the Commissioner re application for funds; proposal by HTA to Hudson superintendent for distribution of funds; letter from NYSUT field representative to HTA chief negotiator, clarifying eligibility for funds
- Hudson-TA Contract, 1988-1996 (Box 11, Folder 52)
  Salary schedules
- Hudson-Incmpetence, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  3020-a charge (incompetence by virtue of failure to maintain certification) by Hudson City School district against tenured teacher; waiver of right to a panel hearing; request for a panel hearing; handwritten notes; correspondence with NYSUT Mid-Hudson regional director
- Hudson-Tenure Denial, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 54)
  Correspondence by NYSUT legal department re tenure denial by Hudson school district; notice of permanent appointment from Ichabod Crane Central School; notice of tenure denial; notice of termination, ostensibly because of budget cuts; elaboration of reasons for tenure denial; observation report
- HTA-Chatham Fair, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 55)
  Agreement 1991-1994 between the Hudson City School District and the Hudson Teachers' Association; memo from district to music, art, technology, and home and career skills teachers re reimbursement for extracurricular events; handwritten notes
- Hudson-TA, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 56)
  Letter suspending teacher and ordering her to obtain a psychiatric examination; letter from district to teacher re lack of valid certification for Italian or Secondary English teaching; letter from district noting successful fulfillment of requirement; letters to district and NYSUT from teacher's personal attorneys; claim for damages from teacher against district
- Hudson-Incentives/Reform and Restructuring (Box 11, Folder 57)
  Text of paper or remarks (by Hudson Teachers Association president Jerry Tschudin?), "Incentives-Reform and Restructuring"
- Chronic Fatigue Syndrome, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 58)
  Application for use of sick leave bank; materials re Chronic Fatigue Syndrome; correspondence from Hudson Teachers Association president re environmental concerns at Hudson High School; grievance re denial of additional time from sick bank
- Hudson-Gym Show, 1983-1991 (Box 11, Folder 59)
  Memorandum of Agreement between district and HTA re John L. Edwards Elementary School Gym Show, January 28, 1984; affidavit by physical education instructors that failure to participate in voluntary Gym Show would not be a strike action; warning by district that refusal to participate would be considered a strike and insubordination, subject to 3020-a action and removal of tenure; related correspondence
- Hudson-Summer School, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 60)
  Notice of Improper Practice charge re summer school program; correspondence re PERB conference and hearing; Verified Answer by district in PERB Improper Practice charge by Hudson Teachers Association against Hudson City School District, with cover letter from attorneys, September 21, 1987; opinion and award in the matter of arbitration between Poughkeepsie Public School Teachers Association (PPSTA) Union and City School District of Poughkeepsie re evening high school work, September 15, 1985
- Hudson-Class Size Grievance, 1980-1987 (Box 11, Folder 61)
  Correspondence between district and HTA over grievance re class size
- HTTA-Job Performance Appraisals, 1990-1992 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  Annual job performance appraisals, 1989-1991; letter of resignation, effective June 30, 1991; arbitration settlement between district and Hunter-Tannersville Teachers Association, January 13, 1992; related correspondence; handwritten notes
- HTTA-Conference Denial, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  Conference description for annual meeting of Association of Mathematics Teachers of NYS; reimbursement form for staff growth activity; past activity forms; cover note from Wagner to NYSUT labor specialist
- HTTA-OWBPA, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  Correspondence by NYSUT labor relations specialist re Older Workers Benefit Protection Act and retirement incentive, alleged discriminatory impact on workers over age 55 with 15 years of service, not offered the incentive; description of Hunter-Tannersville early retirement incentive
- Hunter-Tannersville, 1988-1992 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  Log of services provided by NYSUT field representative to Hunter-Tannersville Teachers Association
- HTTA-Grievance-Letter in File, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  Correspondence between superintendent of schools, Hunter-Tannersville Central School teacher, NYSUT labor relations specialist, and others re grievance
- Agreement and Memorandum, 1978-1984 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  Constitution and By-Laws for the Hunter-Tannersville Central School Teachers' Association
- HTA-Retirement, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  Letter of resignation from director of athletics and teacher of physical education, to qualify for early retirement incentive, October 1, 1986; minutes of board of education meeting, at which resignation and retirement incentive arrangement was accepted, October 2
- HTTA-Bond Issue Election Campaign, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  Steering Committee agendas; phone survey scripts; newspaper clippings; information sheet, Political Action in School Board Elections; mailer re proposed building addition
- HTTA-E.I.T., 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  A Negotiated Agreement between Hunter-Tannersville Central School and Hunter-Tannersville Teachers' Association, July 1, 1984 through June 30, 1987; Agreement between the Superintendent of Schools and the Hunter-Tannersville School Teachers' Association, July 1, 1986 to June 30, 1987, re distribution of Excellence in Teaching aid
- HTA Settlement, 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Settlement summary, February 27, 1991; Memorandum of Agreement re compensation; salary schedules
- HTTA-Termination, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  Notice of termination to probationary teacher, February 3, 1992; list of reasons for termination, February 18, 1992; response by teacher; staff observations, evaluations, and conference reports; response by teacher to staff evaluation; minutes of school board meetings; plan and record of work; handwritten notes
- HTTA-Negotiated Agreement, 1983-1987 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Transcript of hearing with teacher, principal, superintendent, and union representative, July 27, 1983; Negotiated Agreement between Hunter-Tannersville Central School and Hunter-Tannersville Teachers' Association, July 1, 1984 through June 30, 1987
- HTA-Letter f Complaint, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  Letter of complaint re teacher; handwritten note
- Hunter-SRP, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  NYSUT membership enrollment forms (signed); list of school related personnel (aides, school nurse, cafeteria workers, secretaries)
- HTA-Tenure, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  Memo from NYSUT legal counsel Bernard Ashe to NYSUT Mid-Hudson regional director re Hunter-Tannersville teacher Dakin Morehouse re tenure, July 8, 1993; lesson observations and evaluations; minutes of school board meetings, appointing teacher, abolishing his position to allow it to transfer to BOCES, July 17, 1993; teacher resume, transcripts, certifications
- HTA-Basagic/McGuire Pay Grievance Conference, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  Handwritten chronology of events re workshop taken by two teachers, dispute with superintendent over reimbursement, with note re possible grievance; letter showing approval of payment by superintendent
- HTTA-Health Insurance Investigation, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  Catskill Area Schools Employee Benefit Plan (CASEBP) Audit Committee minutes, February 10, 1992; letter from NYSUT labor relations specialist to Hunter-Tannersville superintendent of schools requesting meeting to discuss changes in health insurance plan, need for teachers' association to have direct input to health insurance committee decisions, March 23, 1992
- HTTA-CASEBP Health Insurance Concerns, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  Handwritten notes from meetings; chart showing changes in health insurance plan
- Hunter-Tannersville, 1992-1994 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  Aug. Letter from Hunter-Tannersville Teachers Association chief negotiator to NYSUT regional director objecting to change of labor relations specialist without consultation with local, August 12, 1993; reply from Conti to teachers association president, September 16; Declaration of Impasse, October 3, 1993; PERB notice of appointment of mediator, October 26; NYS Department of Labor notices of safety and health violations, December 1993; incident report, Severe Mistreatment of Teacher by Elementary Principal, February 18, 1992; handwritten memos and notes
- Hunter-Tannersville IP Lesson Plans, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  Memo from NYSUT labor relations specialist re intention to file an Improper Practice charge against the district for failure to negotiate change in terms and conditions of employment re lesson plans, October 7, 1993; letter from NYSUT labor relations specialist to district superintendent, demanding negotiation over lesson plans, October 4; memo, Curriculum Communication, September 7; memo to teachers from district, "Planning," asking for lesson plans, October 1; memo from district, cancelling October 1 memo, October 12; handwritten notes
- HTTA, 1985-1987 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  Materials re dental plan; memo to Hunter-Tannersville Teachers Association (HTTA) co-presidents re NYSUT Benefit Trust program; letter from NYSUT field representative to HTTA, urging members to write to elected state representatives, opposing tuition tax credits (Marchi bill); letters to HTTA from NYSUT Mid-Hudson regional director advising of change in field representative, April and December 1985; school directory; PERB notice of appointment of mediator, May 27, 1987
- Hunter-Tannersville Correspondence, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  Letters to HTTA from NYSUT field representative Harry Fairbanks, suggesting constitution revisions, discussing school nurse issue; related minutes of board meetings; workshop agenda; correspondence re benefit plans; NYSUT contact and service reports re HTTA by Fairbanks
- HTTA, 1987-1993 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  Handwritten tentative agreement, 1988; NYSUT budget analysis of Hunter- Tannersville school district, September 21, 1987; lesson observations and teacher performance evaluations
- Jeffersonville-Youngsville-Budget, 1989-1991 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  Printed proposed school budget, 1991-92; Jeffersonville-Youngsville Central School District no. 1 Summary Evaluation Guidelines; document re classroom observation and annual professional performance review policy and procedure; annual financial reports, fiscal years ended June 30, 1990 and 1989
- Jeffersonville-Youngsville-SRP Contract, 1984-1988 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  Agreements re School-Related Personnel (SRP); PERB fact-finding report; SRP hourly rate comparisons; letter from American Arbitration Association re selection of arbitrator, December 18, 1987; proposed language re teaching assistants; correspondence re negotiations; declaration of impasse; PERB Memorandum on Behalf of the Employer
- Jeffersonville-Youngsville-IP, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  Draft Stipulation of Settlement in Improper Practice case, with cover letter from NYSUT labor relations specialist, September 12, 1990; final settlement, March 20, 1991; related correspondence
- Jeffersonville-Youngsville Agreement, 1989-1992 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  Agreement between Jeffersonville-Youngsville Central School District No. 1, Board of Education and Jeffersonville-Youngsville Central School Faculty Association, Inc., 1989-1992
- Jeffersonville-Youngsville Constitution, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  Faculty association constitution
- JYFA, 1990-1993 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  Memo re agency fee objector Linda Braken; arbitration award re agency fee refund, April 15, 1993; Improper Practice charge against district re teacher over discipline for taking leave time for union activities; correspondence re arbitration over summer curriculum
- KTF-EAP, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  Correspondence re establishing Employee Assistance Program (EAP) for Kingston City School District and Kingston Teachers Federation
- Kingston-Regular Substitutes, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  Commissioner's rulings re filling encumbered positions with per diem substitutes, with cover letter from NYSUT field representative; handwritten notes
- Kingston Teachers Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  Grievance by Kingston Teachers Federation over class size, November 13, 1992; correspondence re other grievances; anonymous one-page document, "Some Interesting Monetary Comparisons," re salaries of school administrators and state governors, signed by "Publius"; memo to NYSUT field representative re attached document based on NYSUT "Conflict in the Classroom" report, describing Kingston situation re disruptive students, May 20, 1993; anonymous document, "The Real Look at the Kingston City Schools Consolidated Budget," signed by "Publius," May 21, 1993; newspaper clippings; notice by PERB of appointment of mediator/fact finder, October 6, 1992; list of outstanding bargaining issues; memo re suspension of special education students, December 16, 1992; memo re problems with transferring disabled students, January 13, 1993; letter to superintendent from teacher requesting transfer to escape harassment by principal, June 18, 1993; newsletters; handwritten correspondence and notes from meetings
- Kingston Teachers, 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  Memo to Mid-Hudson regional director, requesting legal review of possible retirement incentive to avoid layoffs; Stipulation of Settlement withdrawing grievance over reimbursement of employee for medical expenses, February 1991; handwritten notes
- KTF-Memorandum, 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  List of memorandum items (reply by KTF), September 24, 1993; memo re prescription drug coverage, July 27, 1994; agreement document
- KTF "Pool", 1994 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  Letters to individual reading teachers being displaced, notifying them of meeting to bid for vacancies for next academic year, noting seniority status
- KTF, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  Correspondence re use of sick leave bank for maternity leave; denial of leave of absence request for child rearing
- Kingston-Disability, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  Doctor's note re disability related to chemical exposure; request for legal review by NYSUT; related correspondence
- Kingston-Retirement, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  Statement from NYS Teachers' Retirement System re service credit
- Kingston Teachers Correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  Kingston employee newsletter, "The Moxxie Times," January 1991; letter from NYSUT Mid-Hudson regional director to Kingston Teachers' Federation building representative re misleading article in Moxxie Times, "NYSUT Benefits Denied," January 28, 1991; school board (Board of Education) resolutions re appointments of several teachers; handwritten notes
- KTF Constitution (Box 12, Folder 40)
  Constitution of Kingston Teachers' Federation
- KTF-P. Taxter Involuntary Transfer, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  10/31. Grievance re violation of involuntary transfer policy; handwritten notes
- Kingston-Probationary Appointment, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  Collective negotiations agreement; handbook of salary regulations; notice of probationary appointment; revised salary statement; handwritten notes, including chronology
- WAJTA-Grievance, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Annual performance review for teacher, including response to criticisms; board policy re evaluation of instructional staff; grievance re annual performance review
- WAJTA-Conduct Unbecoming, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  Settlement agreement between Windham-Ashland-Jewett Central School District and teacher for five-day suspension without pay and waiver of right to 3020-a hearing; request for legal assistance from NYSUT, describing incident
- WAJTA-Grievance Sick Leave, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  Statement by teacher re docking of one-half day sick leave after taking off part of last period for back pain
- WAJTA-Job Security, 1990-1992 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  Annual performance review; classroom observations; response to teacher's comments; superintendent's response to teachers' association memo, December 17, 1990; Board of Education's response to teachers' association memo, January 10, 1991; request for NYSUT legal review, March 9, 1992; grievance
- Gidance Counselor Issue, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  Correspondence between guidance counselor, schools superintendent, principal, and State Education Department re special arrangements for graduation for failing student, issue of insubordination
- WAJTA-Reprimand, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  Letter of reprimand from superintendent re use of physical force in dealing with student; incident report by teacher
- WAJTA-Retroactive Grievance Pay, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  Grievance for retroactive pay; cover memo
- Windham-TA, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  Teaching certificates, diplomas, transcripts, and resume; correspondence from NYSUT labor relations specialist re special education teacher
- WAJ SRP Notes, 1988-1992 (Box 13, Folder 9)